William Wong



billycwong19@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/williamcwong19



512-905-4340



https://william-wong-portfolio.netlify.app/

Summary

MongoDb, React, Express, and Node (MERN) full-stack developer, trained in HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, and specializing in Single Page Applications. Capable of building full-stack sites from scratch while utilizing design skills with Figma to build wireframes to high fidelity mock-ups.

Experience



Full Stack Engineer

TEK BLOG

2022 - 2022 (1 year)

- Utilized Express, Node, MySQL, and Handlebars.js for a full-stack web
- Integrated a RESTful API architecture for a responsive webpage that's set up for scalability.
- Deployed application to host service Heroku with a MySQL database.

Frontend Developer

PIG-E BANK

2022 - 2022 (1 year)

- Website design and build from wireframe to MVP.
- Used Handlebars.js and Bootstrap for front-end design.
- Worked closely with backend team integrating GitHub for collaboration.

Front End Lead

Karmatic

- · Led front-end team and created mock-ups.
- · Executed code to MVP based on mock-ups using React and Styled-Components
- Communicated with back-end to efficiently write code for production.

Education



UT Austin Boot Camps

Full-Stack Web Development, Computer Science

2022 - 2022

Explored and implemented code in various formats and languages. Learned the MERN stack for creating a website from scratch, back to front.

Berklee College of Music



The Woodlands High School

Licenses & Certifications

Coding Boot Camp Certificate Program - The University of Texas at Austin

React Back to Front - Udemy UC-c1359375-de75-48bf-a05b-31c3e78ed473

JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures Masterclass - Udemy UC-f672e660-b526-4590-9928-b740a0963fb6

Skills

JavaScript • React.js • Node.js • MongoDB • Express.js • styled-components • Bootstrap • Figma (Software) • Next.js • MySQL